<resources>
    <string name="app_name">PocketAid</string>
    <!-- NAV BAR ITEMS -->
    <string name="injuries">Injuries</string>
    <string name="nearby">Nearby Hospitals</string>
    <string name="practice">Interactive Practice</string>
    <string name="about">About</string>

    <!--NAV BAR STATUS? -->
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>

    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- INJURIES -->
    <string name="injury_search"><font size="14">Search for an injury</font></string>
    <string name="fracture">Fracture</string>
    <string name="burns">Burns</string>
    <string name="concussion">Concussion</string>
    <string name="laceration">Laceration</string>
    <string name="contusion">Contusion</string>
    <string name="bites">Bites</string>

    <!-- DOWNLOAD BUTTON -->
    <string name="download">DOWNLOAD</string>
    <string name="download_note">DOWNLOAD VIDEO:</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="stream">STREAM</string>
    <string name="hospitalName">Hospital Name</string>
    <string name="hospitalContactNumber">111111</string>

    <!-- DISCLAIMER -->
    <string name="disclaimer">
        Can this contain a lot of text? Can it contain \n a newline? Yes it can.
        Adding a 2nd line like this should work.
        It should not cause parsing errors
    </string>

    <!-- GROUP NAME -->
    <string name="grp_name">- FUNtastic FOUR</string>

    <!-- SWITCH TEXTS -->
    <string name="Download">Download</string>
    <string name="Downloaded">Downloaded</string>
    <string name="hospitalinfoName">Hospital Name:</string>

    <!-- SPINNER OPTIONS -->
    <string-array name="spinner_options">
        <item>Recommended Procedure</item>
        <item>Alternative Procedure</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- LABELS BURNS -->
    <string name="thermal">THERMAL BURNS</string>
    <string name="electrical">ELECTRICAL BURNS</string>
    <string name="chemical">CHEMICAL BURNS</string>


    <!-- *****************************************
         RECOMMENDED & ALTERNATIVE FIRST AID STEPS
         ***************************************** -->

    <!-- ABRASION -->
        <!-- ABRASION: RECOMMENDED -->
            <string-array name="abrasion_recommended">
                <item>"Wash the affected area with water and anti-bacterial soap."</item>
                <item>"Apply Betadine Solution or Spray."</item>
                <item>"Cover the affected area with gauze or band-aid."</item>
                <item>"Repeat daily until fully healed."</item>
            </string-array>
        <!-- ABRASION: ALTERNATIVE -->
            <string-array name="abrasion_alternative">
                <item>"Boil the guava leaves and run the warm water to the affected area to avoid bacteria."</item>
                <item>"Apply Betadine Solution or Spray."</item>
                <item>"Cover the affected area with gauze or band-aid."</item>
                <item>"Repeat daily until fully healed."</item>
            </string-array>

    <!-- BITES -->
        <!-- ANIMAL BITES: RECOMMENDED -->
            <string-array name="bites_animal_recommended">
                <item>"Control the bleeding by applying pressure on the bite with a clean and dry cloth or handkerchief."</item>
                <item>"Do not clean serious wound. It will be cleaned at a medical facility."</item>
                <item>"Call 911 or use our Nearby Hospital feature."</item>
            </string-array>
        <!-- INSECT BITES: RECOMMENDED -->
            <string-array name="bites_insect_recommended">
                <item>"Check if the bite mark or stinger is swelling and/or bleeding."</item>
                <item>"If there is a stinger, carefully use tweezers, making sure to grab the base of the stinger to prevent squeezing the venom sac."</item>
                <item>"Wash the wound with soap and water."</item>
                <item>"Cover the area with clean bandage or gauze."</item>
                <item>"Apply a cold pack to the affected area to reduce pain and swelling."</item>
                <item>"Call 911 if the person has trouble in breathing or for any other signals of Anaphylaxis (hypersensitivity)."</item>
            </string-array>
        <!-- INSECT BITES: ALTERNATIVE -->
            <string-array name="bites_insect_alternative">
                <item>"Check if the bite mark or stinger is swelling and/or bleeding."</item>
                <item>"If there is a stinger, scrape it away using a flat surface, such as a credit card."</item>
                <item>"Wash the wound with soap and water."</item>
                <item>"Cover the area with a clean handkerchief or cloth."</item>
                <item>"Apply ice cubes wrapped in a clean towel to the affected area to reduce pain and swelling."</item>
                <item>"Call 911 if the person has trouble in breathing or for any other signals of anaphylaxis (hypersensitivity)."</item>
            </string-array>


    <!-- BURNS -->
        <!-- 1ST & 2ND DEGREE BURNS: RECOMMENDED -->
            <string-array name="burns_thermal_recommended">
                <item>"Hold the burned area in running water for 5 to 10 minutes or until pain is relieved."</item>
                <item>"Cover the burn with a dry, non-sticking, sterile dressing or a clean cloth."</item>
                <item>"Keep the burned area clean by washing with a mild soap and water."</item>
            </string-array>
            <string-array name="burns_chemical_recommended">
                <item>"Immediately remove the chemical by flushing with water."</item>
                <item>"Remove the victim's contaminated clothing while flushing with water."</item>
                <item>"Flush for 20 minutes or longer. Let the victim wash with a mild soap before final rinse."</item>
                <item>"Cover the burned area with a dry dressing or, for large areas, a clean pillow case."</item>
                <item>"If the chemical is in the eye, flood it for at least 20 minutes using low-pressured water. Preferably running water."</item>
                <item>"Seek medical attention immediately for all chemical burns."</item>
            </string-array>
            <string-array name="burns_electrical_recommended">
                <item>"Unplug, disconnect, or turn off the power. If that is impossible, call the power company or ask for help."</item>
                <item>"Seek medical attention immediately. Electrical injuries are treated in burn center."</item>
            </string-array>
        <!-- 1ST & 2ND DEGREE BURNS: ALTERNATIVE -->
            <string-array name="burns_thermal_alternative">
                <item>"Apply a clean towel dampened with a cool tap water."</item>
                <item>"Cover any small blisters with a loose bandage, or gauze, and tape."</item>
                <item>"Keep the burned area clean by washing with a mild soap and water."</item>
            </string-array>
        <!-- 3RD DEGREE BURNS: RECOMMENDED -->
            <string-array name="burns_third_recommended">
                <item>"Protect the burned person from further harm."</item>
                <item>"Remove jeweleries, belts, and other restrictive items especially from around the burned areas and the neck."</item>
                <item>"Do not immerse large severe burns in cold water."</item>
                <item>"Elevate the burned area. Raise the wound above heart level, if possible."</item>
                <item>"Call 911 or use our Nearby Hospitals feature immediately."</item>
            </string-array>

            <!-- NOTES -->
                <string-array name="burns_third_notes">
                    <item>"If you can do so safely, make sure the person you\'re helping is not
                            in contact with smoldering materials or exposed to smoke or heat. But do not remove burned clothing stuck to the skin."</item>
                    <item>"Burned areas swell rapidly."</item>
                    <item>"Doing so could cause a serious loss of body heat (hypothermia) or a drop in blood pressure and
                            decreased blood flow (shock)."</item>
                    <item>""</item>
                    <item>""</item>
                </string-array>
        <!-- 3RD DEGREE BURNS: ALTERNATIVE -->
            <string-array name="burns_third_alternative">
                <item>"Protect the burned person from further harm. If you can do so safely, make sure the person you\'re helping is not
                        in contact with smoldering materials or exposed to smoke or heat. But do not remove burned clothing stuck to the skin."</item>
                <item>"Remove jeweleries, belts, and other restrictive items, especially from around the burned areas and the neck. Burned areas swell rapidly."</item>
                <item>"Cover the burn with a dry, non-sticking, sterile dressing or a clean cloth."</item>
                <item>"Treat the victim for shock by elevating the legs and keeping the victim warm with a clean sheet or blanket."</item>
                <item>"Call 911 or use our Nearby Hospitals feature immediately."</item>
            </string-array>


    <!-- CONCUSSION -->
        <!-- CONCUSSION: RECOMMENDED -->
            <string-array name="concussion_recommended">
                <item>"Apply cold compress or cold pack to the injured area for 20 minutes every 3 hours."</item>
                <item>"Observe your child carefully for the next 24 hours. If there are any signs of internal injury, call 911 or use our Nearby Hospital feature."</item>
            </string-array>


    <!-- CONTUSION -->
        <!-- CONTUSION: RECOMMENDED -->
            <string-array name="contusion_recommended">
                <item>"Apply a cold pack, or ice wrapped in a clean towel, for up to 15 minutes on the bruise to help reduce swelling."</item>
                <item>"Keep the bruised area raised above the heart, if possible, to keep the blood from pooling in the bruised tissue."</item>
                <item>"Try to rest the bruised part by not overworking the certain area."</item>
                <item>"If needed, take acetaminophen (Tylenol) to help reduce the pain."</item>
            </string-array>


    <!-- FRACTURE -->
        <!-- FRACTURE: RECOMMENDED -->
            <string-array name="fracture_recommended">
                <item>"In the case of an open wound, control the bleeding and cover the wound with a sterile dressing; if a bone is protruding, use a ring pad then apply a bandage making sure it is not directly over the fracture."</item>
                <item>"Support the fractured limb in the most comfortable position. Raise and rest a fractured foot or ankle on pillows or folded blankets."</item>
                <item>"Immobilize the fractured limbs using a splint or sling. Do not attempt to straighten the fractured limb."</item>
                <item>"Check regularly that the bandages are not too tight, affecting circulation."</item>
                <item>"Watch for signs of shock."</item>
                <item>"Call 911 or use our Nearby Hospital feature."</item>
            </string-array>


    <!-- LACERATION -->
        <!-- MAJOR LACERATION: RECOMMENDED -->
            <string-array name="laceration_major_recommended">
                <item>"Put on disposable gloves. If you suspect that blood might splatter, you may need to wear eye and face protection."</item>
                <item>"Control the bleeding by:
                    (a) covering the wound with a dressing and firmly pressing against the wound until the bleeding stops or
                    (b) applying a pressure bandage over the dressing to maintain pressure on the wound and to hold the dressing in place.

                    If blood soaks through the bandage, do not remove the blood-soaked bandages. Instead, add more dressings and bandages and apply additional direct pressure."</item>
                <item>"Continue to monitor the person\'s condition. Observe the person closely for signals that may indicate that the person\'s condition is worsening
                    such as faster or slower breathing, changes in skin color and restlessness."</item>
                <item>"Care for shock. Keep the person from getting chilled or overheated."</item>
                <item>"Have the person rest comfortable and provide reassurance."</item>
                <item>"Wash your hands immediately after giving care, even if you wore gloves."</item>
            </string-array>
        <!-- MINOR LACERATION: RECOMMENDED -->
            <string-array name="laceration_minor_recommended">
                <item>"Use disposable gloves and place a sterile dressing on the wound."</item>
                <item>"Apply direct pressure for a few minutes to control any bleeding."</item>
                <item>"Wash the wound thoroughly with soap and water. If possible, wash out an abrasion for about 5 minutes with clean, warm, running tap water."</item>
                <item>"Apply an antibiotic ointment to a minor wound if the person has no known allergies or sensitivities to the medication."</item>
                <item>"Cover the wound with a sterile dressing and a bandage or with an adhesive bandage to keep the wound moist and prevent drying."</item>
            </string-array>
        <!-- MINOR LACERATION: ALTERNATIVE -->
            <string-array name="laceration_minor_alternative">
                <item>"Wash your hands with soap and water. Use any clean barrier between your hand and the wound if gloves is not available."</item>
                <item>"Apply direct pressure and press firmly against the wound. Use a clean cloth or handkerchief to apply pressure."</item>
                <item>"Clean and cover the wound with a clean cloth or handkerchief."</item>
            </string-array>


    <!-- PUNCTURE -->
        <!-- SEVERE PUNCTURE: RECOMMENDED -->
            <string-array name="puncture_severe_recommended">
                <item>"Wash your hands with soap and water then wear gloves."</item>
                <item>"Apply direct pressure to the affected area using a sterile gauze."</item>
                <item>"Clean and cover the wound with a sterile gauze."</item>
                <item>"Consult and refer to a physician immediately if the bleeding doesn't stop."</item>
            </string-array>
        <!-- SEVERE PUNCTURE: ALTERNATIVE -->
            <string-array name="puncture_severe_alternative">
                <item>"Wash your hands with soap and water. If gloves are note available, use any clean barrier between your hand and the wound."</item>
                <item>"Apply direct pressure and press firmly against the wound. If sterile gauze is not available, use your hand or a clean cloth or handkerchief to apply pressure."</item>
                <item>"Clean and cover the wound with a clean cloth or handkerchief."</item>
                <item>"If the cloth becomes soaked with blood, do not remove it. Apply addition clean cloth on top."</item>
                <item>"Consult and refer to a physician immediately if the bleeding doesn't stop."</item>
            </string-array>
        <!-- SLIGHT PUNCTURE: RECOMMENDED -->
            <string-array name="puncture_slight_recommended">
                <item>"Wash your hands with soap and water then wear gloves."</item>
                <item>"Clean the wound with soap and water."</item>
                <item>"Apply mild antiseptic or antibiotic cream."</item>
                <item>"Cover the wound loosely with sterile gauze or bandage."</item>
            </string-array>
</resources>
